## RyanLandman

For the past 12 years I've worked both in-house and within an agency environment developing responsive websites and web applications for all types of clients. My focus is in front-end development (though I do have expericence with back-end development, primarily PHP and Wordpress). I've found that my background in graphic design has helped me collaborate effectively with designers to bridge the gap between creative and development.



P: 610-585-4590
E: ryan.landman@gmail.com
W: ryanlandman.com

## Experience

April 2019 - May 2020

1600ver90

Senior Front End Developer / Interim Tech Lead

In addition to my provious responsibilities at 160ever90. Lyang a

In addition to my previous responsibilities at 160over90, I was also tasked with leading client conversations around technology/recommending solutions, mentoring Junior Developers, and improving the efficiency of the development process. During this time I worked closely with Producers to implement a process for accurately scoping development effort while eliminating scope creep throughout the UX/Design phases. I also developed a framework for rapidly building landing pages using a collection of components common to all historical projects.

April 2018 - April 2019 6 160over90 Front End Developer

Developed client websites for both higher education and consumer clients with an emphasis on web accessibility best practices and WCAG 2.1 compliance. I worked closely with the Design team to translate atomic design systems into scalable and mainatainable component libraries, leveraging Vue.js for all interactivity. Clients included: Blue Origin, The Philadelphia Zoo, LSU, Jefferson University, University of Pennsylvania, and Rowan University.

June 2017 - April 2018 🖕 Quattro

Senior Web Developer

Responsible for front and back-end development of all internal and client web sites (Wordpress and static), as well as landing pages and emails with Hubspot integration. I also managed and mentored a Junior Developer/QA Analyst.

Front End Developer

Responsible for front and back-end development of all internal and client web sites.

Education University of the Arts

BFA Graphic Design, 2008

Philadelphia, PA

Skills
HTML CSS JavaScript Vue.js PHP Twig Web Accessibility
Wordpress Photoshop Illustrator Sketch Project Management